ALEX STRUGACZ

COMPUTER PROGRAMMER



847-922-3054



alexstrugacz@icloud.com



alexstrugacz.com

PROFILE

Hello! I am an actively studying prospective Computer Science student interested in undergraduate research, studying abroad, debate, and **coffee**. My goal: to use computer science to make lives healthier, happier, and more safe, literally and figuratively from my dorm (or the nearest library).

SKILLS

- Team Leadership
- JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, C/C++, Python, Java
- SwiftUI, Swift, Xcode, VSCode, Git, Notion, Figma
- UI/UX Design
- · Project Management

EDUCATION

JOHN HERSEY HIGH SCHOOL

August 2020 - June 2024

- GPA: 3.95, 4.43
- 12 AP Courses, 7 Honors

AP COMPUTER SCIENCE A

August 2022 - June 2023

• Grade Received: A

AP COMPUTER SCIENCE PRINCIPLES

August 2021 - June 2022

• Self-Studied, Score: 5

HONORS

- Presidential Volunteer Service Award, Gold
- National Merit Commended
- AP Scholar with Distinction
- A-Honor Roll (x6)

EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Normandy Remodeling

January 2023 - Present

- Built back-end infrastructure to gather and aggregate 30,000 calendar data points from 96 employees daily
- Replaced deprecated contact book software by coding a rolodex to display, filter, and edit over 500 company contacts
- Communicated with CEO and CTO weekly to tailor my work
- Assisted in onboarding new employees to my codebase

FOUNDER AND PROJECT LEAD

Hersey Developers 501(c)(3)

December 2022 - Present

- Provided work-based learning experiences in computer science to 18 interns from our local community
- Mentored interns working on 3 programming projects designed to be used by students and staff in our school (ex. Chess Team Game Tracker)
- Worked with district administrators on necessary funding, advertisement, and infrastructure resources
- Created an educational model that has received inquiries for local. state, and national expansion.

HARVARD CS50 AND CS50T COMPUTER SCIENCE

Harvard University

October 2021 - March 2022

- Enrolled in Harvard University's Intro to Computer Science class
- Attended lectures virtually while working alongside other local and international students
- Advanced my knowledge computer science on the base level (bits, binary, random access memory, and transistors)